<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>afrodiplomacy</title>
    <description>afrodiplomacy</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2025 18:12:13 +0200</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2025 18:12:13 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v4.4.1</generator><item>
        <title>West Africa Projects</title>
        <description>&lt;p class=&quot;intro&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;dropcap&quot;&gt;A&lt;/span&gt; lot of infrastructure projects are planning for West Africa in the years/decades to come. These projects will for sure shape the future of West Africa.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Contents&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Abidjan - Lagos corridor&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;West Africa pipeline&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Transsaharan pipeline&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Abidjan-Lagos corridor
I remember when I was a teenager, I traveled with my parents from Abidjan to Cotonou by road and I remember it was one of the best roadtrips I’ve taken in my life so far.
This trip is definitely amazing, you cross borders and get to see a huge diversity in the people you come accross with, the foods, the smells are very different from one place to another. And the sight and breeze of the Atlantic ocean throughout the whole journey is absolutely amazing. Of course, you need to be in a good car with good comfort to really enjoy the journey. And of course they are other downsides like every roadtrip: lack of resting infrastructure and information about hotels, bad roads, pickpockets, …
So, back to the Abidjan-Lagos corridor. It consists on a high-speed highway from Abidjan to Lagos, accross the Atlantic ocean, through Accra, Lomé and Cotonou.
When fully implemented, this corridor will dramastically reduce transit time from one city to another accross the corridor. It will boost economic integration between the major economies of the region and positively impact the populations close to this corridor and beyond.
It was originally due in XXXX but nowadays, ECOWAS plans to fully finalize this project by XXXX.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;West African (gas) pipeline
This project is led by the Moroccan and Nigerian governements and also all the governments of Benin, Togo, Ghana, Sierra Leone, Liberia, Guinea, Senegal, Mauritania in which the gas pipeline should transit when the project is terminated. As the Russia/Ukraine war is ongoing, Europe needs to diversify its gas proivisionning partners and Nigeria is known in Africa to be one of major oil producer and its gas production is set to dramatically increase in the years to come.
Morocco would then sell Nigerian gas to its European counterparts through pipeline or harbours terminals connecting Africa to Europe.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Transsaharan pipeline
Another project set to impact greatly the West African region is the Trans-Saharan pipeline. This project aims to export Nigerian gas through the countries of Niger and Algeria. This project is my humble opinion very difficult to achieve as it would transit throughout the whole Sahara desert and also face terrorists/djihadists groups in the region.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description><description>&lt;p class=&quot;intro&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;dropcap&quot;&gt;A&lt;/span&gt; lot of infrastructure projects are planning for West Africa in the years/decades to come. These projects will for sure shape the future of West Africa.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/WestAfricaProjects/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/WestAfricaProjects/</guid></item><item>
        <title>Oldies of Africa</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Mensah Musa representation, on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Catalan_Atlas&quot;&gt;Catalan Atlas&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/mansahmusa.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tata Somba, in Benin
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/oldies_africa/tatasomba_benin.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Benin bronzes, British Museum
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/oldies_africa/beninbronzes_britishmuseum.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Graffiti wall, Cotonou
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/oldies_africa/graffitiwall1_cotonou.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/oldies_africa/graffitiwall2_cotonou.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/oldies_africa/graffitiwall3_cotonou.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/oldies_africa/graffitiwall4_cotonou.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description><description>&lt;p&gt;Mensah Musa representation, on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Catalan_Atlas&quot;&gt;Catalan Atlas&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/mansahmusa.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/OldiesOfAfrica/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/OldiesOfAfrica/</guid></item><item>
        <title>Every African man should have</title>
        <description>&lt;p class=&quot;intro&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;dropcap&quot;&gt;B&lt;/span&gt;ecause education is key to raise a new generation of African leaders to build wealth, prosperity and peace in their countries&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I was raised into a grown-up man, I feel like I’ve always missed a “paternal figure” in my life. I belive thousands if not millions of Africans can relate to that experience. Sad thing is, you can easily waste some years of your life by not having the good advice or mentor in the moment of your life you need it. Been there, lived that. This blog post is based on my own experience and relates what an African male should do in his life to try to be more successful. Again, I believe success is a very relative concept. One can have million of dollars in his bank account and feel he’s not successed in life, and someone else only a few bucks and dozens of children and feels like he’s the king of universe. Again, this list is only based on my own criterias; but I’m sure many of you can relate to it !&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By 18&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;ID documents (ID card + Passport)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Baccalaureat / WAEC&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Speak fluently one foreign language (French/English/Spanish/Mandarin/Italian)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By 25&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Driving licence&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Learn how to plan a budget&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Basic computer skills (Word/Excel/Drive/Programming)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By 30&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Travel to one foreign country (in Africa, Europe, US, Middle East or elsewhere), the point is to travel and get out of his comfort zone&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Transportation mean (motorbike, car, bicycle)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By 35&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Parcel of land&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By 40&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Be married, have a family and raise kids&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Items to own (no age constraints)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A watch&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A suit&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pair of shoes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Swiss knife&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Toolbox (mechanic/random)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description><description>&lt;p class=&quot;intro&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;dropcap&quot;&gt;B&lt;/span&gt;ecause education is key to raise a new generation of African leaders to build wealth, prosperity and peace in their countries&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/EveryManShouldHave/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/EveryManShouldHave/</guid></item><item>
        <title>USA/Africa relationship</title>
        <description>&lt;p class=&quot;intro&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;dropcap&quot;&gt;T&lt;/span&gt;he United Nations projects that by 2050, Africa&apos;s population will reach close to 2.5 billion. Such a figure would mean that more than 25 percent of the world&apos;s population will be African. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.imf.org/-/media/Files/Publications/Fandd/Article/2023/September/Picture-this-0923.ashx&quot;&gt;Source&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve never traveled to the United States
But USA has been somehow present in all my life
From childhood, cinema, music, culture, clothes we wear
Even in Europe, USA influence has been very present&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As for the relationship with Africa, Obama seemed a promise
But Africa got very few things there, even nothing at all&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But there are of course good aspects of it
Ghana year of return is actually a good one
I see much more African American people coming to Africa, for Detty December for example
Mostly African immigrants who have settled for one, two, three generations already in the US
There is the same thing in Europe, but sadly low income and very expensive flight tickets to Africa dont help the movement to grow further&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Benin, also announced granting citizenship to all people from African descent over the globe&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Those initiaves in my view give much more credit and are in the way of getting USA people and African people closer. Yes I know, for now it’s mainly US people from African descent.
Let’s not forget that USA has been also very active in the religious and humanitarian fields.
We used to see thousand of USAID and other humanitarian organizations coming to Africa, heping build dwells and schools for the local people. Well, some of my fellow Africans friends seem to doubt about the real intentions behind those acts of generosity. Maybe it’s also a way to explore potential oil fields, or other mineral resources. Who knows ?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For sure, African culture has been very critized in the past, and nowadays, since we see actions of POTUS willing to annex and tax everyone, a lot of people throughout the world will become nationalist and I think it iwll for sure benefit Africa in some ways. We will also understand that we need to build on our own resources, whether there are local or living in the diasporas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;African music is booming also in the US and across the globe. It is funny how a  lot of African American people can relate to the music made in Africa, especially Afrobeats. I guess it will be one of the major source of connection between the USA and Africa, not to mention of course that many of the top players in the NBA league are originated from Africa.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also check the Lobito corridor
WW2 bombs uranium was originated from Africa
USA has many military bases in Africa
USA Africa military command AFRICOM is in Germany ? What possible changes under the Trump administration ?&lt;/p&gt;
</description><description>&lt;p class=&quot;intro&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;dropcap&quot;&gt;T&lt;/span&gt;he United Nations projects that by 2050, Africa&apos;s population will reach close to 2.5 billion. Such a figure would mean that more than 25 percent of the world&apos;s population will be African. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.imf.org/-/media/Files/Publications/Fandd/Article/2023/September/Picture-this-0923.ashx&quot;&gt;Source&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/USA_Africa/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/USA_Africa/</guid></item><item>
        <title>Donald Trump and Africa</title>
        <description>&lt;p class=&quot;intro&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;dropcap&quot;&gt;T&lt;/span&gt;he United Nations projects that by 2050, Africa&apos;s population will reach close to 2.5 billion. Such a figure would mean that more than 25 percent of the world&apos;s population will be African. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.imf.org/-/media/Files/Publications/Fandd/Article/2023/September/Picture-this-0923.ashx&quot;&gt;Source&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the US policy towards Africa is guided by the super head of only one person, namely: Donald J. Trump, let’s try to dig in his mind and understand what will be the US administration policy towards Africa.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“They are eating the dogs, they are eating the cats !”
Sounds pretty normal to me, if one has nothing to eat, doesn’t have the right to work and earn money for a living and feed himself and his family.
USA and the Western world are probably the exception ! In …countries of out …., people can eat dogs and cats. Even the Chinese !!!!&lt;/p&gt;

</description><description>&lt;p class=&quot;intro&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;dropcap&quot;&gt;T&lt;/span&gt;he United Nations projects that by 2050, Africa&apos;s population will reach close to 2.5 billion. Such a figure would mean that more than 25 percent of the world&apos;s population will be African. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.imf.org/-/media/Files/Publications/Fandd/Article/2023/September/Picture-this-0923.ashx&quot;&gt;Source&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/Trump_Africa/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/Trump_Africa/</guid></item><item>
        <title>The winners and losers of Globalism</title>
        <description>&lt;p class=&quot;intro&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;dropcap&quot;&gt;T&lt;/span&gt;he United Nations projects that by 2050, Africa&apos;s population will reach close to 2.5 billion. Such a figure would mean that more than 25 percent of the world&apos;s population will be African. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.imf.org/-/media/Files/Publications/Fandd/Article/2023/September/Picture-this-0923.ashx&quot;&gt;Source&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Who are the winners and losers of Globalism ?&lt;/p&gt;

</description><description>&lt;p class=&quot;intro&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;dropcap&quot;&gt;T&lt;/span&gt;he United Nations projects that by 2050, Africa&apos;s population will reach close to 2.5 billion. Such a figure would mean that more than 25 percent of the world&apos;s population will be African. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.imf.org/-/media/Files/Publications/Fandd/Article/2023/September/Picture-this-0923.ashx&quot;&gt;Source&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/TheWinnersOfGlobalism/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/TheWinnersOfGlobalism/</guid></item><item>
        <title>The return of the Far West in Geopolitics and Economy</title>
        <description>&lt;p class=&quot;intro&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;dropcap&quot;&gt;T&lt;/span&gt;he United Nations projects that by 2050, Africa&apos;s population will reach close to 2.5 billion. Such a figure would mean that more than 25 percent of the world&apos;s population will be African. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.imf.org/-/media/Files/Publications/Fandd/Article/2023/September/Picture-this-0923.ashx&quot;&gt;Source&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Content:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Greenland&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Canada annexion&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Tarrifs on USA, China&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description><description>&lt;p class=&quot;intro&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;dropcap&quot;&gt;T&lt;/span&gt;he United Nations projects that by 2050, Africa&apos;s population will reach close to 2.5 billion. Such a figure would mean that more than 25 percent of the world&apos;s population will be African. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.imf.org/-/media/Files/Publications/Fandd/Article/2023/September/Picture-this-0923.ashx&quot;&gt;Source&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/TheGlobalFarWest/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/TheGlobalFarWest/</guid></item><item>
        <title>The Niger/France crisis</title>
        <description>&lt;p class=&quot;intro&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;dropcap&quot;&gt;T&lt;/span&gt;he United Nations projects that by 2050, Africa&apos;s population will reach close to 2.5 billion. Such a figure would mean that more than 25 percent of the world&apos;s population will be African. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.imf.org/-/media/Files/Publications/Fandd/Article/2023/September/Picture-this-0923.ashx&quot;&gt;Source&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The images of Nigerien population storming the French embassy in Niamey and raising Nigerien and Russian flags will last for long. To my humble knowledge, it is one of the biggest failures of French diplomacy over the last decades. Hôtel Ivoire retaliation/massacre is another one, but might be attribuable more to the French army than to the French  Diplomacy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s recap the situation in Niamey to understand what are the French diplomacy mistakes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;There is a coup d’état in Niamey as president elected Mohamed Bazoum is being held in his residence by General Tiany who is the capitain of the National Guard which controls the presidential palace. From what we’ve heard, Bazoum was at the point of sacking General Tiany and replace him with someone else and Tiany didn’t like that. Behind the scenes, petrol has been discovered in Niger and it’s been told that Bazoum wanted to give the exploitation contracts to a French company. Tiany doesn’t see things tht way, because uranium has been exploited by French companies for decades and Nigerien people got almost nothing from it. Former president Issoufou seems to also have taken some part in this coup !&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;In this chaotic situation, French president Emmanuel Macron tries to onboard the regional group (ECOWAS) on a military intervention on Niger soil to re-establish Bazoum as president. Well, the thing is ECOWAS is an economic organization and not a military one and this so-called military intervention to reinstate democracy is ‘nipped in the bud’. This military intervention could’t take place because no country in ECOWAS has enough military manpower to overtake Niger alone, except Nigeria… But it’s almost impossible to see some Nigerian Haoussa military men fight Haoussa Nigerien military brothers over some French governement directives. North of Nigeria is home to millions of inhabitatants trading daily with their Nigerien counterparts. A military intervention would put the whole region of more than 50 million inhabitants in chaos. And traditional kings of the region settles some meetings and prevented this intervention to happen. Apparently the weight of traditional powers was neglected. First error of the French diplomacy.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;French ambassador in Niger have been known lately to be very communicative over his social medias (namely Twitter) against “so-called panafricanist influencers” and tried his best to show the benefits of French and European collaboration to the people of Niger. One thing he couldn’t change is the ranking of Niger in (10) least developed countries in the World. But the Nigerien people know for sure that their uranium empowers a big percentage of France energy mix. And sadly they saw almost no benefit from it. Neither the so-called corrupt political elite. Otherwise, there would have been very wealthy Nigerien elite people, which I’m unaware of. Or those wealthy people would have sponsored a lot of demonstration in Niger against the military regime. Well, at some point, Nigerien people directed their anger towards French ambassador Syvain Itté. And stormed the upskirts of the French embassy, raising placards saying that French military and ambassador should go! Before that, the military regim has declared the French ambassador ‘persona non grata’ and told him he had 48 hours to leave the country. French president said at that time that he wouldn’t leave and that the military regime was not legitimate while his ambassador was, so the regime had to leave instead of the ambassador. Second error of the French diplomacy is to not have perceived that the population was in favour of the military regime. They were probably more busy having some buffets “au caviar et au champagne” !&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Let’s focus now on the last error of the French diplomacy. Niger is a country of 1,26 millions km square and one of top ten countries with GDP increase in the world. The Chinese have discovered oil and built a pipeline from Niger to Cotonou. There will be a huge growth in the population of Niger where women have 7/8 kids in average. They will need good education,  healthcare, leisure, energy; tourism will grow, and they need expertise in almost all fields. France and European countries have that expertise. It would have been very wise to keep economic ties with Niger hoping the political tensions will be resolved in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For my part, I am more than eager to collaborate with associations and people of Niger and also associations and people from France to foster economic growth for the benefits of both populations. Feel free to contact me for beneficial opportunities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vive le Niger !
Vive la France !&lt;/p&gt;
</description><description>&lt;p class=&quot;intro&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;dropcap&quot;&gt;T&lt;/span&gt;he United Nations projects that by 2050, Africa&apos;s population will reach close to 2.5 billion. Such a figure would mean that more than 25 percent of the world&apos;s population will be African. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.imf.org/-/media/Files/Publications/Fandd/Article/2023/September/Picture-this-0923.ashx&quot;&gt;Source&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/Niger_France_UraniumCrisis/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/Niger_France_UraniumCrisis/</guid></item><item>
        <title>Mr Elon Musk</title>
        <description>&lt;p class=&quot;intro&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;dropcap&quot;&gt;Mr&lt;/span&gt; Musk is someone that you&apos;ve heard of, whether you like him or not. His businesses are very successful, making him the richest man on earth. But one thing most people ignore about him is that he is born in Apartheid South Africa and is originally South African, thus his vision of the world!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mr Elon Musk is born in Apartheid South Africa. For those who don’t know, what is Apartheid South Africa ?
A ountry located in the southern part of Africa in which thousands if not millions of Europeans have emigrated, exterminate some local populations, took property of their lands, and put them under the rule of segregation in their own country for decades. These Europeans were mostly coming from the Netherlands, Germany, Ireland, France, Poland, …
Mr Musk’s father has also “acquired” a diamond mine and became rich, so rich to put his kids in private white-only South African schools at that time. Elon graduated and emigrated first to Canada where he acquired citizenship and then to the USA when he also acquired American citizenship.
I feel like Elon n his latests remarks and attitude, really show that his world vision is derivated from Apartheid, where the rich, white people bring civilization to the world and have power against the poors and are legitimate to colonize every place they desire (even Mars) in order to keep their power and dominance.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><description>&lt;p class=&quot;intro&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;dropcap&quot;&gt;Mr&lt;/span&gt; Musk is someone that you&apos;ve heard of, whether you like him or not. His businesses are very successful, making him the richest man on earth. But one thing most people ignore about him is that he is born in Apartheid South Africa and is originally South African, thus his vision of the world!&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/MrMusk_Afrikaner/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/MrMusk_Afrikaner/</guid></item><item>
        <title>ECOWAS vs AES</title>
        <description>&lt;p class=&quot;intro&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;dropcap&quot;&gt;T&lt;/span&gt;here is definitely a leadership competition in West Africa right now. As millions of people are struggling to survive, a new organization is born from the Sahel region. Will AES be able to bring prospertity and stability to the people of West Africa ?&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After decades of war against terrorists and separatifs, “Coup d’Etat” have put military officers and generals as head of states of the countries of Mali, Burkina-Faso and Niger. Even though the people oof those countries are still struggling to defeat terrorism within their borders, it is very clear that those military regims have ben backed by the people of those countries. Never in the last 20 years have we seen people demonstrations and protests to quick military presence of foreign countries like the ones we’ve seen in Niamey in ?????.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a wind of “dégagisme” that is clearly visible and coming from the Sahel towards the south like “l’Harmattan”. To such a point that Senegal elected a young populist vice/president and even Ivory Coast had to take back the biggest foreign base in the region (namely 43ème BIMA) and renamed it after an Ivoirian General.
Now, let’s stick to the people of West Africa aspirations. With an estimated population of around 500 millions, West African populations desperately need basic resources; water, energy, health, and security. On top of that, certainly free trade and free movement of persons and goods. The average age of those populations is like 15/16 years old. Thousands or millions of young people get to the job market every year and are forced to take either low payed jobs like taxi/motor driver, nails technician, in order to put food on the table by the end of the day, for themselves and their families.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When they had enough of this struggle, many are tempted to migrate to Europe or the Americas to the peril of their lives. This desperation has been going on for decades. They’ve had enough of the countless fake elections, unkept politican promises, and are desperetaly needing for change, whatever might it be. It is therefore no surprising that they’ve gathered by thousands in front of the French embassy in Niamey to ask for the expell of the ambassador, whom attitude was full of condescendance, not remembering that “he is the guest, not the host”.
In the West, people seem to not understand, that the West Africans people are tired of neing exploited and are fully aware they are the “vache laitière” of so many countries and people around the Globe. They are fully aware that their uranium empower some G7 countries, and that DRC uranium was used for WW3 atomic bombs, and so on, and so forth… The “real size of Africa” pretty much relates in my humble opinion how countries are benefitting from Africa at its expense.&lt;/p&gt;

</description><description>&lt;p class=&quot;intro&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;dropcap&quot;&gt;T&lt;/span&gt;here is definitely a leadership competition in West Africa right now. As millions of people are struggling to survive, a new organization is born from the Sahel region. Will AES be able to bring prospertity and stability to the people of West Africa ?&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/ECOWAS_vs_AES/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/ECOWAS_vs_AES/</guid></item></channel>
</rss>
